# Devanshu Kumar Verma

Software Consultant



✓ vermadevanshu145@gmail.com

← +91 7078146612 ## 15/04/2000 Indian

**@** Unmarried 💄 Male

#### **Profile**

Meticulous web developer with over 2 years of front end experience and passion for responsive website design and a firm believer in the mobile-first approach. Implemented new responsive website approach which increased mobile traffic by 20%. I do have experience in technologies like HTML, CSS, Javascript, Jquery, Angular, ReactJs, DJango looking forward to learn and explore more into web.

#### **Education**

**B.tech,** KIET Group of Institutions 2017 - 2021 | Ghaziabad, India Information Technology

12th, Don Bosco Senior Secondary 2016 - 2017 | Gorakhpur, UP, India

10th, Nav jeevan mission school 2014 - 2015 | Deoria, UP, India

### Languages

English

Hindi

# **Interests**

Reading books (Philosophy novels), **Cooking** (North Indian and South Indian)

## **Professional Experience**

**React developer,** ServicesBazar

07/2020 - 06/2021

My role as developer here is to develop and design frontend of servicesBazar app using react.js and python at backend

**Software Consultant, Knoldus Inc** 07/2021 - 07/2022 | Noida, UP, India My role here is to design and develop frontend of the webApps and Websites.I have experience making portals and microsites for brand promotion of clients.

**Angular developer,** *Applore technology* 07/2022 - 11/2022 | Noida, India

**Software Engineer - UI,** Gojoko technologies 11/2022 - present | Noida, India As a UI Software Engineer at Gojoko Technology, I optimized performance of our Angular app using accessibility and performance best practices, reducing the build size by 50%. I improved the website's SEO with advanced Angular concepts like SSR and PWA. I introduced the Tailwind CSS framework to the team.

#### **Skills**

Angular Frontend JS Framework	•	•	•	•	
<b>Django</b> Python based full stack web framework	•	•	•	•	
HTML	•	•	•	•	
css	•	•	•	•	
<b>Tailwind</b> CSS framework	•	•	•	•	
<b>Bootstrap</b> CSS framework	•	•	•	•	
Javascript	•	•	•	•	
<b>Reactjs</b> Frontend JS framework	•	•	•	•	
Nextis	•	•	•		

Frontend Js Framework